Priti Patel

Tel: 267-391-5142

Patelpr_03@Yahoo.Com



Summary:

As IT Professional with over 10 years of experience in tech support system, administration, deployment, maintaining, upgrading, configuring network operating systems, troubleshooting hardware, network servers, storage and computer peripherals for medium to large corporate environments.

Education:

- Associate of Computer Network Technology, Bucks County Community College, Newtown PA
- Bachelor of Science, Nagpur University, India
- Master of Science, in Textile, Nagpur University, India

Certification:

- The Coding Boot Camp at UT Austin (Expected completion Jan 2022)
- Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA)
- VMware Certified Associate Data Center Virtualization
- · Certificate, Network Administrator, Bucks County community College, Newtown, PA
- Certificate, Computer hardware Installation/Maintenance, BCCC, Newtown, PA

Skills:

- Good understanding of different available Software's, Packages, Security Tools.
- Good knowledge and troubleshooting methodology.
- Knowledge of MySQL, Linux, DNS, database queries and java programming
- Experience of network infrastructure, installations and design.
- Experience of SAS and RAID server storage technology.
- Knowledge of TCP/IP SMTP, IP, SNMP, HTTP and routing protocols with Cisco routers
- Knowledge of configuring client PC systems for performance testing.
- Knowledge and experience of Routing Protocols: EGRP, BGP, RIP, IS-IS, OSPF
- Expertise in Analysis of Problems and providing solutions.
- Excellent communication & interpersonal skills and efficient team player.
- Well organized and ability to work flexible working hours and travel if required.

Technical Skills:

Operating System: Windows, Unix, and macOS

Software: AD, VB, .Net, Lync, SharePoint, Microsoft Office, Remote Desktop Services, MS Project,

Adobe Creative Suite

Hardware: Compaq, Dell, Intel and IBM Servers, POS Hardware, workstations and Laptops

Protocols: RIP, RIPv2, EIGRP, OSPF, BGP, LDP, MPLS, and MP-BGP

Switching Technology: VLAN, VTP, DTP, STP, PVST, RSTP, Ether Channel, IP Access Control list Cisco

Catalyst 3750, 3560 and Cisco 5508 controllers

Network Technology: LAN, WAN, VPN, Wireless Networking, VoIP, T1, and MPLS

Cloud Technology: Amazon AWS EC2, Office 365, Google Apps, Microsoft Azure

Work Experience:

IT Service Desk Specialist

July 2021 - Present

Progressive Insurance

Austin, TX

Provide technical support to restore failed IT service as quickly as possible. Manage ITSM documents used by the IT Service Desk to troubleshoot end user issues. Identify potential outages then contact appropriate personnel. Record and classify received incidents along with logging efforts taken to correct issue.

Responsibilities:

- Diagnose, troubleshoot and resolve a range of software, hardware and connectivity issues. Excel in asking probing questions and researching, analyzing and rectifying problems.
- Accurately diagnosed, documented, and resolved hardware, software, mobile device, application, peripheral, remote
- Supported the Total Performance Management initiative of insurance claims systems
- Resolved complex problems according to escalation procedure

Software Technical Support

Harte Hanks

Austin, TX Sep 2016 - Jan 2020

The technical frontline support agent provides a vital service to the Customer Service Technical Support. Resolution of all reported issues via troubleshooting, escalation, research, or collaboration

Responsibilities:

- Managed day to day steady-state operations, acting as focal point for any and all issues with customer
- Giving coaching and providing guidance to customers assistance in their use of technology tools
- Perform with direction, problem verification by confirming a customer's environment, error messages, and symptoms of a problem.
- Assist customers with installation, backup/restore, configurations, and implementations of software
- Diagnose and resolve desktop, software, and network problems related to functionality, connectivity, management, and monitoring, or other software and hardware problems.
- Researching moderate to complex cases using knowledge bases documentation.
- Preparing, recommending, and guiding the customer through implementing solutions.

Tech Support Analyst
Bucks County Community College
Newtown, PA

Jan 2009 - Feb 2015

To provide an innovative, customer service, and strong foundation for information technology (IT) solutions that enables the Community College to pursue excellence in research, education, and public service. Build and maintain positive relationships with students, faculty, staff and all internal departments to deliver a high level of service.

Responsibilities:

- Assisted students, faculty and staff with downloading and installing software, testing and to allow staff access applications from home.
- Giving coaching and providing guidance to students, faculty and staff receive assistance in their use of technology tools computer skill, technology assistance and training.
- Hardware support for administrative staff and faculty computers and networking
- Operations and maintenance of the data and voice networks, including voice mail service
- Custom programming, research, and systems integration with Datatel and web-based Database Systems
- Work with respective departments who request database services and provide training on use of database applications and the campus intranet
- Help manage and support faculty, students and staff using course and portal delivery technologies including Canvas & D2L, along with integration with other Learning Management tools.
- Manage basic network administration by creating and maintaining user and resource network accounts with appropriate security settings

Network Engineer Global Soft Tech Inc Woodbridge NJ

Nov 07- Dec-08

Used technical expertise to plan, configure, engineer, and troubleshoot network configuration changes on remotely located routers, switches, cisco ASA firewalls and F5 load balancers. Execute network change and project requests supporting complex environments.

Responsibilities:

- Implemented and configured all network upgrades and Cisco ASA Firewall
- Installed network devices as well as management of devices involved in a Frame Relay WAN/LAN/MAN
- Manage areas of networking and systems deployment, including monitoring, Troubleshooting, and usage reporting, WAN /LAN connectivity and routing and Firewall.
- Monitoring of Data Communication systems, bandwidth, and health of the network using tools Cisco works and Sniffer
- Responsible for maintaining routing Protocols (BGP, OSPF, Spanning Tree) and switching infrastructure.
- Responsible for daily operations, Problem management, system backups, layered product, software upgrades, hardware maintenance, and system security.
- Create and regularly refine backup protocols to ensure data and network integrity.

IT Support

Aquarium Pharmaceuticals, Inc

Chalfont, PA March 07- May 07

Supported the Information Technology Manager in installations, troubleshooting maintenance and setting up software on the standalone and networked computers

Responsibilities:

- Managed Active Directory and group policies to manage users, computers and software.
- Installed and maintained entire network, including cabling for the office as well as preparing computer resources including servers, workstations, laptops, printers, and equipment
- Responsible for install, configure, maintain updating and repair hardware and software.
- To restore information from Backup tape utilizing veritas Backup Exec.
- To setup Outlook for remote access for office associates and remote users.
- Works on issues with hardware, software, printers, desktops, servers and network.